[Music]
hi everyone welcome back to the channel
this video is ample hills coffee toffee
coffee
ample hills a us brand do great flavors
got a great ethos
coffee
is a big thing in this house especially
for me i can't do anything without a cup
of coffee in the morning
toffee
and more coffee coffee toffee coffee i
wonder how many times i say coffee in
this video let's put a counter up here
somewhere anyway if you want to know how
to make it stick around we'll show you
[Music]
so for this ice cream put your
ingredients in a pan and warm them
gently add in your 10 grams of instant
espresso powder and heat to 65 degrees
or whatever temperature your stabilizer
needs if you don't want to use
stabilizers you can just leave them out
once up to temperature remove from the
heat and add your cream
and then put it in a fridge to cool
completely
[Music]
for the toffee put 250 grams of butter
and 200 grams of sugar in a pan and get
it melting i've added five grams of
espresso powder here it won't combine
until the sugars and butter do but don't
worry it will just sit on top up until
that stage
get it all up to 125 to 130 degrees c at
which point you can pour into a decent
sized pan lined with baking parchment
i've used an 8x8 but to be honest a
slightly larger would have been better
leave that to cool completely then melt
your 100 grams of milk chocolate and add
one teaspoon of pure coffee extract mix
that well and spread over the toffee
cool it completely in the fridge and
then put it in the freezer
when your base is chilled get it
churning as usual now's the time to
remove your chocolate covered toffee
from the freezer and smash it up or chop
it into small pieces put them in a tub
and put them straight back in the
freezer as we don't want them to get
soft at this stage
[Music]
when it's all completely churned load
your tub as normal layering with the
coffee ice cream and the toffee pieces
when it's filled put it in the freezer
for at least three hours
[Music]
straight out the freezer along get some
of that ice off
look at that tub
this is whitty chicken apparently going
to ample hills
what a witty name
anyway let's get some scooped up into a
bowl and see what it looks like
[Music]
i mean it looks great for a start
doesn't it i mean deep coffee ice cream
what is coffee toffee coffee it's a dark
coffee ice cream with espresso infused
chocolate covered toffee pieces
now i couldn't really find any details
about where the espresso and coffee
flavoring is they do make a point that
they only use real espresso powder and
natural coffee extract so that's what
we've done here but because i can't get
that exact i've put coffee and
everything coffee and the ice cream
coffee in the toffee coffee and the
chocolate so
there's a lot of caffeine in here which
is probably not what i need right now
so let's just dig in and see what it
tastes like
[Music]
this
oh
that is a good ice cream
big coffee fan anyway
so
only really make this one if you like
coffee
like the last one mint if you didn't
like mint don't try that if you don't
like coffee really don't try this one
the coffee flavor is a real punch in the
ice cream super smooth texture
slight little chew to it too which is
really nice
the toffee
now i adjusted the toffee just a little
bit to make it a little bit
fudge like so it's not rock hard
when you bite through it you even frozen
straight at the freezer you can actually
bite through the toffee without breaking
the teeth
you get that coffee extract come through
in the chocolate as well
all in all are really nice i mean nice
as an understatement
an excellent package of coffee chocolate
and toffee
we must be up to what 30 times by now i
don't know
ample hills
great artwork for their tubs as well
this is not going to be the first one of
theirs or the last one of theirs that we
make so stick around if you want to see
some more ample hills flavors made
anyway i hope you've enjoyed this video
stick around next week we're going to
make a boozy haagen-dazs one
thanks for watching and take care